UNESCO Second Canadian Archaeological Expedition to Carthage Records MS210
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
UNESCO Second Canadian Archaeological Expedition to Carthage Records
1978 -- 2002
1905 -- 2008
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Wells, C. M. (Colin Michael)
MS210
26.55 Linear Feet
1424 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into six series: Records and Reports from the Carthage digs; Field journals; Fiche reports; Excavation site images; Carthage site maps; and Carthage site drawings.
Biographical / Historical
Colin Michael Wells was born on November 15, 1933 in West Bridgford, Notts, England. He attended Oriel College, Oxford from 1952 to 1954 before joining the Royal Artillery stationed in Egypt and Germany. Following his military service, he received his BA in 1958 from Oriel College, Oxford. In 1960, Wells accepted a position teaching at the University of Ottawa. He earned his doctorate in 1965 under the tutelage of Professor Ian Richmond.
Beginning in 1976, Wells led a team of researchers in excavations at Carthage. The initial excavations were part of an UNESCO campaign entitled "Save Carthage." The excavations focused on the Theodosian Wall and continued through 1986. In 1987, Wells went to Trinity University as the first Murchison Distinguished Professor of Classical Studies. In this role, he continued excavations at Carthage using the Odeon Hill site as an educational opportunity for Trinity students through 2002.
In addition to his archaeological work, Wells was a scholar of Roman frontiers and military under Augustus. He wrote and edited four books and over 120 articles examining the Roman frontier and army, Roman Africa, and changes in the empire under Augustan military activity.
Wells retired from Trinity University in 2004 after serving as chair of the classical studies department and as a member of several university committees. He was given the title of professor emeritus.
Wells married Kate Hughes in 1960. They had two sons, Christopher and Dominic. Wells passed away on March 11, 2010 at Banger in North Wales.
Custodial History
This collection was donated to DCA in February 2014 by Kate Wells, widow of C.M. (Colin Michael) Wells. From 1976 to 1986 C.M. Wells was director of the UNESCO Second Canadian Archaeological Expedition to Carthage in modern Tunisia. C.M. Wells died in March 2010 before completing a final report on the excavations, and the Wells family asked R. Bruce Hitchner, Professor of Classics and International Relations at Tufts, to continue the project. At Hitchner's request, the collection was transferred from Kate Wells to DCA to enable his research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains archaeological records, reports, field journals, small find reports, excavation site images, maps, tracings of mosaics and drawings from the UNESCO Second Canadian Archaeological Expedition to Carthage, led by Colin Wells. The records primarily cover the dig on section 2CC on the Northern Sector Theodosian Wall from of 1976 and 1986.
Faculty research; Excavations (Archaeology)
- Records and Reports from the Carthage digs, 1965 -- 2008; MS210.001; 6.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records from 1965-1999, from UNESCO's Second Canadian Archaeological dig led by Colin Wells at the 2CC Northern Sector of the Theodosian wall. The records primarily include Colin Wells's publications, reports, articles, and correspondence detailing the dig's efforts at the sites. Interspersed among the records are also plans, drawings, and black and white prints that may have corresponding material in other series.
  This series also contains records from the archaeological dig sponsored by Trinity University and led by Colin Wells at the Hill of Odeon. These records include dig notes, records, and trench information.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically by date.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Colin Wells Publications, 1965 -- 1999; MS210.001.029.00023 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Cahier D'Arpentage 1976, MS210.001.031.00001 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '76 - Cahiers copies, 1976; MS210.001.031.00002 (Box 31)
  - 2CC - Plans, Drawings, etc., 1976; MS210.001.031.00003 (Box 31)
  - Reports 1976, MS210.001.031.00004 (Box 31)
  - Carthage - Correspondence 1976 season, MS210.001.031.00005 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '76 B&W Prints, 1976; MS210.001.031.00006 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Own Reports 1976 - 1983, MS210.001.031.00007 (Box 31)
  - 2CC - Pottery articles, Jentel, Neuru, 1977 -- 1980; MS210.001.031.00008 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Relevant articles, 1976 -- 1987; MS210.001.031.00009 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '78, 1978; MS210.001.031.00010 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '78 B&W Prints, 1978; MS210.001.031.00011 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Faunal Remains, 1978 -- 1982; MS210.001.031.00012 (Box 31)
  - 2CC - Burials, 1978 -- 1986; MS210.001.031.00013 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Mosaics, 1978 -- 1983; MS210.001.031.00014 (Box 31)
  - Reports on Trenches, 1978 -- 1989; MS210.001.031.00015 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '79 - Application and correspondence, 1979; MS210.001.031.00016 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '79, 1979; MS210.001.031.00017 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '79 M.T., 1979; MS210.001.031.00018 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '79 B&W Prints, 1979; MS210.001.031.00019 (Box 31)
  - Carthage photos, MS210.001.031.00020 (Box 31)
  - Carthage Comparanda, 1979 -- 1986; MS210.001.031.00021 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Inscriptions, 1980; MS210.001.031.00022 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '80, 1980; MS210.001.031.00023 (Box 31)
  - 2CC '80 M.T., 1980; MS210.001.031.00024 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Worked Bone, 1980 -- 1986; MS210.001.031.00025 (Box 31)
  - 2CC Glass, 1980 -- 1989; MS210.001.031.00026 (Box 31)
  - Preliminary Excavation Notes 1981, MS210.001.032.00001 (Box 32)
  - 2CC '81, 1981; MS210.001.032.00002 (Box 32)
  - 2CC2F '81, 1981; MS210.001.032.00003 (Box 32)
  - Reports on Carthage 1981, 1997, MS210.001.032.00004 (Box 32)
  - INAA & Workmens, 1981 -- 1983; MS210.001.032.00005 (Box 32)
  - Wightman, 1981 -- 1984; MS210.001.032.00006 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Coins, 1981 -- 1984; MS210.001.032.00007 (Box 32)
  - Other Correspondence, 1981 -- 1985; MS210.001.032.00008 (Box 32)
  - Other Team Members, 1981 -- 1987; MS210.001.032.00009 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Mastaba Tomb, 1981 -- 1983; MS210.001.032.00010 (Box 32)
  - Drawings 1982, MS210.001.032.00011 (Box 32)
  - Jurmain, 1982; MS210.001.032.00012 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Cisterns, 1982; MS210.001.032.00013 (Box 32)
  - 2CC '82, 1982; MS210.001.032.00014 (Box 32)
  - 2CC '82 M.T., 1982; MS210.001.032.00015 (Box 32)
  - Pottery (WCINDA), 1982 -- 1983; MS210.001.032.00016 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Geological, 1982 -- 1983; MS210.001.032.00017 (Box 32)
  - SSHRCC, 1982 -- 1988; MS210.001.032.00018 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Pottery (J.F.), 1982 -- 1989; MS210.001.032.00019 (Box 32)
  - Freed, 1983; MS210.001.032.00020 (Box 32)
  - Frosst & Jago, 1983 -- 1984; MS210.001.032.00021 (Box 32)
  - Caroll - Spillecke, 1984; MS210.001.032.00022 (Box 32)
  - Hayes, 1984 -- 1991; MS210.001.032.00023 (Box 32)
  - Carthage 1985 Correspondence, MS210.001.032.00024 (Box 32)
  - Carthage 1985, MS210.001.032.00025 (Box 32)
  - Carthage 1985 (Caramigue), MS210.001.032.00026 (Box 32)
  - Carthage - Own Work '85 & '86, 1985 -- 1986; MS210.001.032.00027 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Pottery - Post-Doc. & Res. Grant Reports, 1985 -- 1987; MS210.001.032.00028 (Box 32)
  - Carthage 1986, MS210.001.032.00029 (Box 32)
  - Carthage Spring '86, 1986; MS210.001.032.00030 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Fresco, 1986; MS210.001.032.00031 (Box 32)
  - 2CC A.A. Paper 12-1987, MS210.001.032.00032 (Box 32)
  - Carthage Houses, 1988; MS210.001.032.00033 (Box 32)
  - 2CC CNV Art. 1988, MS210.001.032.00034 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Skeletons, 1988; MS210.001.032.00035 (Box 32)
  - Carthage - Trinity, 1988 -- 1992; MS210.001.032.00036 (Box 32)
  - Carthage - Cedac Vol., 1989 -- 1998; MS210.001.032.00037 (Box 32)
  - Working Notes and Papers for 2CC, 1989 -- 1991; MS210.001.032.00038 (Box 32)
  - Ennabli - INAA, 1922 -- 1989; MS210.001.032.00039 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Workmens, 1989 -- 1996; MS210.001.032.00040 (Box 32)
  - 2CC, A metallurgical study by Henry Unglik, 1980 -- 1989; MS210.001.032.00041 (Box 32)
  - Preliminary Report on Trenches c. 1981, MS210.001.032.00042 (Box 32)
  - Trenches E.M.W. (2CC), 1980 -- 1989; MS210.001.032.00043 (Box 32)
  - 2CC Mudbrick, 1980 -- 1989; MS210.001.032.00044 (Box 32)
  - 2CC6/TVC - Own Notes, 1990; MS210.001.033.00001 (Box 33)
  - 2CC9, 1990; MS210.001.033.00002 (Box 33)
  - Hector Relief, 1990 -- 1991; MS210.001.033.00003 (Box 33)
  - Carthage '90 - '91 Reports, 1990 -- 1991; MS210.001.033.00004 (Box 33)
  - Antiquarium & Mise-en-Valeur, 1990 -- 1991; MS210.001.033.00005 (Box 33)
  - Carthage - Travel & Admin, 1990 -- 1992; MS210.001.033.00006 (Box 33)
  - Garrison - Correspondence, 1991; MS210.001.033.00007 (Box 33)
  - Pottery Exhibit (J2P), 1991; MS210.001.033.00008 (Box 33)
  - Bldg A., 1991; MS210.001.033.00009 (Box 33)
  - 2CC6/TVC - Plans, 1992; MS210.001.033.00010 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Reports (Michigan Cemetery), 1992; MS210.001.033.00011 (Box 33)
  - 2CC (JBG), 1992 -- 1994; MS210.001.033.00012 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Foundations, 1993 -- 1997; MS210.001.033.00013 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Data, 1993 -- 1998; MS210.001.033.00014 (Box 33)
  - Carthage - Rick's Notes, 1994; MS210.001.033.00015 (Box 33)
  - Suggested Odeon Trenches 1994, MS210.001.033.00016 (Box 33)
  - Odeon - 1994 Dig Records, etc., MS210.001.033.00017 (Box 33)
  - AIA 1994 Own paper, MS210.001.033.00018 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1994 Administration, MS210.001.033.00019 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Coins (K.H.), 1994 -- 1998; MS210.001.033.00020 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1995 Administration, MS210.001.033.00021 (Box 33)
  - Odeon - 1995 Dig Records, etc., MS210.001.033.00022 (Box 33)
  - 2CC8, 1996; MS210.001.033.00023 (Box 33)
  - Worked Bone, 1996; MS210.001.033.00024 (Box 33)
  - Independent Study - Baxter 1996, MS210.001.033.00025 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1996 - Dig Records, MS210.001.033.00026 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Administration & Correspondence, 1996; MS210.001.033.00027 (Box 33)
  - 2CC8, 1997; MS210.001.033.00028 (Box 33)
  - James Cook Trench 2CC5, 1997; MS210.001.033.00029 (Box 33)
  - John Stillwell ODN Cavea, ODN4 - 4a, 2CC8, 1997; MS210.001.033.00030 (Box 33)
  - Clint Chamberlain & Mindy Spearman Trenches: 2CC6 (F95 f, g), ODN6, 6T, 6U, 1997; MS210.001.033.00031 (Box 33)
  - Tim Mills Trenches ODN9, 9A, 9B, 9C, 1997; MS210.001.033.00032 (Box 33)
  - Carthage: Articles, 1997; MS210.001.033.00033 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1997 - Admin & Planning, MS210.001.033.00034 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1998 Administration, MS210.001.033.00035 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1998 Odeon Plans, MS210.001.033.00036 (Box 33)
  - Carthage 1998 Records, MS210.001.033.00037 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Fiches, 1997 -- 1998; MS210.001.033.00038 (Box 33)
  - Carthage Papers: The Early Colony's Economy, Water Supply, a Public Bath, and the Mobilization of State Olive Oil, 1998; MS210.001.033.00039 (Box 33)
  - Carthage administrative, 1999; MS210.001.035.00001 (Box 35)
  - Carthage ODN, 1999; MS210.001.035.00002 (Box 35)
  - Carthage ODN Trinity Records, 1999; MS210.001.035.00003 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Letters and Addresses, 2000; MS210.001.035.00004 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Dig Records, 2000; MS210.001.035.00005 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Information and Xeroxes, 2000 -- 2001; MS210.001.035.00006 (Box 35)
  - Carthage, 2001; MS210.001.035.00007 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Presentation Information, 2000; MS210.001.035.00008 (Box 35)
  - Carthage travel, 2002; MS210.001.035.00009 (Box 35)
  - 2CC1/2 Glass, 2006 -- 2008; MS210.001.035.00010 (Box 35)
  - Odeon Hill and Odeon, MS210.001.035.00011 (Box 35)
  - Odeon Hill maps and photographs, MS210.001.035.00012 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Michigan photographs, MS210.001.035.00013 (Box 35)
  - Carthage area maps, MS210.001.035.00014 (Box 35)
  - 2CC Final Report overview, 1980 -- 1991; MS210.001.035.00015 (Box 35)
  - Carthage maps and photos, MS210.001.035.00016 (Box 35)
  - 2CC team photos, 1978; MS210.001.035.00017 (Box 35)
  - Costisella Collections, MS210.001.035.00018 (Box 35)
  - Pottery charts (JZF), MS210.001.035.00019 (Box 35)
  - Drawings (Chris Morris), MS210.001.035.00020 (Box 35)
  - Carthage Museum information, MS210.001.035.00021 (Box 35)
- Field Journals, 1976 -- 1998; MS210.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains field journals from 1976-1998 from UNESCO's Second Canadian Archaeological dig at the 2CC Northern Sector of the Theodosian wall and at the archaeological dig sponsored by Trinity University at the Hill of Odeon. The field journals are bound volumes where members of the archaeological team detailed the daily dig efforts, described small finds, and drew on-site maps. Authors of the journals include Colin Wells, Marianne Goodfellow, and Gerald Pelletier.
  - CC2 1976 and MT 1978, 1976 -- 1978; MS210.002.030.00001 (Box 30)
  - Cellard 1978, MS210.002.030.00002 (Box 30)
  - Demers 1978, MS210.002.030.00003 (Box 30)
  - Gallagher 1978, MS210.002.030.00004 (Box 30)
  - Kyle 1978, MS210.002.030.00005 (Box 30)
  - Pelletier 1978 I, MS210.002.030.00006 (Box 30)
  - Pelletier 1978 II, MS210.002.030.00007 (Box 30)
  - K. Wells 1978, MS210.002.030.00008 (Box 30)
  - Bennett 1979, MS210.002.030.00009 (Box 30)
  - Conrad 1979, MS210.002.030.00010 (Box 30)
  - Curchin 1979, MS210.002.030.00011 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1979 I, MS210.002.030.00012 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1979 II, MS210.002.030.00013 (Box 30)
  - Leclerc 1979, MS210.002.030.00014 (Box 30)
  - Pelletier 1979 I, MS210.002.030.00015 (Box 30)
  - Pelletier 1979 II, MS210.002.030.00016 (Box 30)
  - 2CC1/2 1979, MS210.002.030.00017 (Box 30)
  - 2CC 1980 Goodfellow I, MS210.002.030.00018 (Box 30)
  - 2CC 1980 Goodfellow II, MS210.002.030.00019 (Box 30)
  - 2CC 1980 Pelletier, MS210.002.030.00020 (Box 30)
  - 2CC1/2 1980, MS210.002.030.00021 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1981 I, MS210.002.030.00022 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1981 II, MS210.002.030.00023 (Box 30)
  - 2CC 1982 Goodfellow I, MS210.002.030.00024 (Box 30)
  - 2CC 1982 Goodfellow II, MS210.002.030.00025 (Box 30)
  - McIntosh 1982 I, MS210.002.030.00026 (Box 30)
  - McIntosh and Ben Mhd. Amar 1982 & 1983 II, MS210.002.030.00027 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1983 I, MS210.002.030.00028 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1983 II, MS210.002.030.00029 (Box 30)
  - 2CC3 1983 & 2CC2 Q, U, V, MS210.002.030.00030 (Box 30)
  - Barrie 1986, MS210.002.030.00031 (Box 30)
  - Bell 1986, MS210.002.030.00032 (Box 30)
  - Clark 1986, MS210.002.030.00033 (Box 30)
  - Goodfellow 1986, MS210.002.030.00034 (Box 30)
  - Sherman 1986, MS210.002.030.00035 (Box 30)
  - Wickens 1986, MS210.002.030.00036 (Box 30)
  - Wells 1994, 1995, 1996, 1998, 1994 -- 1998; MS210.002.030.00037 (Box 30)
  - Field Journal 1994 I, MS210.002.030.00038 (Box 30)
  - Field Journal 1994 II, MS210.002.030.00039 (Box 30)
  - Field Journal 1994 III, MS210.002.030.00040 (Box 30)
  - Baxter 1995, MS210.002.030.00041 (Box 30)
  - Corrigan 1995, MS210.002.030.00042 (Box 30)
  - Mills 1995, MS210.002.030.00043 (Box 30)
  - Palmarg 1995, MS210.002.030.00044 (Box 30)
  - Rodgers 1995, MS210.002.030.00045 (Box 30)
  - Scott 1995, MS210.002.030.00046 (Box 30)
  - Mark 1998, MS210.002.030.00047 (Box 30)
- Fiche reports, 1976 -- 1998; MS210.003; 5.35 Linear Feet
  This series contains fiche reports from 1976-1998, pertaining to sections of UNESCO's Second Canadian Archaeological dig at the 2CC Northern Sector of the Theodosian wall, and small finds (menues trouvailles) and fiches from the archaeological dig sponsored by Trinity University at the Hill of Odeon. There are a few indices to the small finds sheets, particularly for the earlier years. Included at the end are reports and fiche specifically for material finds such as bone, shell, glass, stone, mosaics, and metal.
  This series is arranged by fiche type, then by location, and then chronologically.
  - 2CC 1D, 1976; MS210.003.026.00001 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1D, 1976 -- 1979; MS210.003.026.00002 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1E, 1976; MS210.003.026.00003 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1E 1F, 1976 -- 1979; MS210.003.026.00004 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1F 1G 1H, 1976; MS210.003.026.00005 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1G, 1976 -- 1979; MS210.003.026.00006 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1H, 1976 -- 1982; MS210.003.026.00007 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1J, 1980 -- 1983; MS210.003.026.00008 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1K, 1978 -- 1980; MS210.003.026.00009 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1L, 1978 -- 1979; MS210.003.026.00010 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1M, 1978 -- 1980; MS210.003.026.00011 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1N, 1978 -- 1983; MS210.003.026.00012 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1R, 1978 -- 1980; MS210.003.026.00013 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1S, 1979 -- 1980; MS210.003.026.00014 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1T, 1976 -- 1981; MS210.003.026.00015 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1U, 1979 -- 1983; MS210.003.026.00016 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 1V 1Y, 1983; MS210.003.026.00017 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 2A 2B 2C, 1982 -- 1986; MS210.003.026.00018 (Box 26)
  - 2CC 2C 2D, 1976; MS210.003.026.00019 (Box 26)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [1 of 3], 1983; MS210.003.027.00001 (Box 27)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [2 of 3], 1983; MS210.003.027.00002 (Box 27)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [3 of 3], 1983; MS210.003.027.00003 (Box 27)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.), 1986; MS210.003.027.00004 (Box 27)
  - List of layers of current work, 1985; MS210.003.027.00005 (Box 27)
  - Index to pottery small piece pages, 1985; MS210.003.027.00006 (Box 27)
  - Pottery small piece pages, 1983; MS210.003.027.00007 (Box 27)
  - Pottery small piece pages, 1983; MS210.003.027.00008 (Box 27)
  - Pottery small piece pages, 1983; MS210.003.027.00009 (Box 27)
  - Pottery small piece pages, 1982 -- 1983; MS210.003.027.00010 (Box 27)
  - Pottery small piece pages, 1985; MS210.003.027.00011 (Box 27)
  - Fiches done by Joann Freed, Mylene Francescon, 1979 -- 1987; MS210.003.027.00012 (Box 27)
  - Copies of fiches done, 1985 -- 1986; MS210.003.027.00013 (Box 27)
  - Copies of fiches done, 1985 -- 1986; MS210.003.027.00014 (Box 27)
  - Copies of fiches done, 1985 -- 1986; MS210.003.027.00015 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1978; MS210.003.027.00016 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1979; MS210.003.027.00017 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1980; MS210.003.027.00018 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1981; MS210.003.027.00019 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1982; MS210.003.027.00020 (Box 27)
  - 2CC M.T., 1983 -- 1986; MS210.003.027.00021 (Box 27)
  - Unglik, Copper Alloys, La Tierra, Cores and Points, 1992; MS210.003.027.00022 (Box 27)
  - 2CC 2D, 1978 -- 1980; MS210.003.028.00001 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2E, 1976 -- 1982; MS210.003.028.00002 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2E 2F, 1976; MS210.003.028.00003 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2F bis, 1981 -- 1982; MS210.003.028.00004 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2F, 1978 -- 1986; MS210.003.028.00005 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2G, 1979; MS210.003.028.00006 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2H, 1979 -- 1986; MS210.003.028.00007 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2J 2L 2P 2Q, 1978 -- 1986; MS210.003.028.00008 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2N, 1981 -- 1983; MS210.003.028.00009 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2S, 1981 -- 1982; MS210.003.028.00010 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2T, 1983 -- 1986; MS210.003.028.00011 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2U 2V, 1983; MS210.003.028.00012 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 2X, 1983; MS210.003.028.00013 (Box 28)
  - 2CC 3A 3B, 1983; MS210.003.028.00014 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [1 of 2], 1980; MS210.003.028.00015 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [2 of 2], 1980; MS210.003.028.00016 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [1 of 2], 1981; MS210.003.028.00017 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [2 of 2], 1981; MS210.003.028.00018 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [1 of 2], 1982; MS210.003.028.00019 (Box 28)
  - Journal Des Menues Trouvailles (2CC Journal M. T.) [2 of 2], 1982; MS210.003.028.00020 (Box 28)
  - 2CC Bone, Shell, and Skeletal Remains, 1978 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00001 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Glass and Terra Cotta, 1976 -- 1983; MS210.003.029.00002 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Marble Stone and Construction Material, 1978 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00003 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Metal including Coins, 1976 -- 1983; MS210.003.029.00004 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Mosaic and Fresco, 1976 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00005 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC Worked Bone and Stone, Jetons, Misc., 1976 -- 1983; MS210.003.029.00006 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Coins RBH, 1976 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00007 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Coins RCB, 1976 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00008 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Metal Finds, 1976 -- 1982; MS210.003.029.00009 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Duplicate Copies, Small Finds Catalogue [1 of 2], 1976 -- 1981; MS210.003.029.00010 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Duplicate Copies, Small Finds Catalogue [2 of 2], 1976 -- 1981; MS210.003.029.00011 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - 2CC1/2CC2 Menues Trouvailles, 1979; MS210.003.029.00012 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Small Finds, 1979; MS210.003.029.00013 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [1 of 6], 1995 -- 1998; MS210.003.029.00014 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [2 of 6], 1995 -- 1997; MS210.003.029.00015 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [3 of 6], 1997; MS210.003.029.00016 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [4 of 6], 1976 -- 1998; MS210.003.029.00017 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [5 of 6], 1995 -- 1998; MS210.003.029.00018 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Odeon Hill Fiches [6 of 6], 1994; MS210.003.029.00019 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Carthage files, 1998; MS210.003.029.00020 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Fiches to be filed [1 of 2], 1981 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00021 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Fiches to be filed [2 of 2], 1981 -- 1986; MS210.003.029.00022 (Box MS210 Shared 1)
  - Small Finds Catalogue Cross-Referenced by Strata, 1978 -- 1979; MS210.003.035.00001 (Box 35)
- Excavation site images, 1905 -- 2002; MS210.004; 7.45 Linear Feet; 1424 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains photographs, slides and images taken of the excavation sites from 1976-2002 at both the UNESCO's Second Canadian Archaeological dig at the 2CC Northern Sector of the Theodosian wall and at the archaeological dig sponsored by Trinity University at the Hill of Odeon. It also contains materials used for exhibits of the UNESCO Second Canadian Archaeological Expedition to Carthage. At the end of the series are images of other archaeological sites unrelated to the digs led by Colin Wells.
  This series is arranged by location and then roughly chronologically.
  - Exhibit material and images, MS210.004.00001 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 2)
  - Exhibit material and images, MS210.004.00002 (Box Small Map Case 1 Drawer 1)
  - 2CC Plans and finds, 1976 -- 1995; MS210.004.001
    - 2CC Plans and Finds, MS210.004.001.00001 (Box 1)
      - House 1, MS210.004.001.00001.00001; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
        Slides (photographs)
      - House 1, MS210.004.001.00001.00002; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - House 1, MS210.004.001.00001.00003; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Theodosian Wall, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00004; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Theodosian Wall, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00005; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Theodosian Wall, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00006; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00007; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00008; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00009; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00010; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00011; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00012; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - Main Site, Northern Sector, MS210.004.001.00001.00013; Wells, Colin (Box 1)
      - 2CC78 plan 2CC6, MS210.004.001.00001.00014; Wells, Colin (Box 1)